# SANDESH G. BHAT

# $m mrs and esh bhat. github. io \\ m Tempe, AZ$

(+1) 480 410 9626  $\diamond$  sandesh.bhat@asu.edu

Sandesh Bhat is a Ph.D. candidate in the Systems Engineering program at the Polytechnic Campus. He has worked on many proposals with Dr. Sangram Redkar in the field of Prostheses and mechanical design. With his experience in working on new ideas and projects, he understands the efforts needed to bring an idea to fruition. His academic details are as listed below:

# **EDUCATION**

Arizona State University, U.S.A.

January 2018 - Present

Doctor of Philosophy

GPA: 4/4

Department of Systems Engineering

Arizona State University, U.S.A.

August 2016 - December 2017

Master of Science in Mechanical Engineering

GPA: 3.44/4

Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering

Mumbai University, India

August 2012 - May 2016

Bachelors in Engineering

CGPA: 7.71/10

Department of Mechanical Engineering

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Graduate Teaching Assistant

August 2019 - December 2019

Arizona State University

· Teaching Assistant for EGR 217 and EGR 343. Both courses revolved around Mechanics and Strength of Materials.

# **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

August 2018 - May 2019

Arizona State University

· Instructed and guided undergraduate students in Matlab, C and other computational programming languages for EGR 219: Computational Modelling of Engineering Systems.

## Graduate Research Assistant

August 2017 - December 2018

Arizona State University

- · Worked in the Robotics, Dynamical Systems and Controls Group as a Ph.D. student under Dr. Sangram Redkar and Dr. Thomas Sugar.
- · Designed and Developed a Passive Prosthetic Ankle under a Small Business Innovation Research grant.
- · Worked on Universal Robots 5 and Baxter platforms and guided undergraduate students on the same.
- · Worked on multiple proposals with Dr. Redkar.

# Control System Modelling and Simulation Engineer

September 2016 - June 2017

AZLoop - A Hyperloop Competition Team

- · Leaded the Control System Modelling and Simulation sub-team of 8 engineers at AZLoop for the SpaceX Hyperloop Competition.
- · Worked on the levitation system control modelling and simulation.

# RESEARCH CONTRIBUTIONS

Analysis of a periodic force applied to the trunk to assist walking gait

SG Bhat, S Cherangara, J Olson, S Redkar, TG Sugar

2019 WearRAcon

Design and Analysis of an Auto-Parametrically Excited Platform for Active Vibration Control

T Le, SG Bhat, SC Subramanian, P Waswa, S Redkar

ASME 2019 IDETC-CIE

Volitional control of an active prosthetic ankle: a survey

2018

2019

SG Bhat, S Redkar

International Robotics and Automation Journal

Development of a Passive Prosthetic Ankle With Slope Adapting Capabilities 2018 SG Bhat, S Redkar, TG Sugar ASME 2018 IMECE

### POSITION OF RESPONSIBILITY

## Graduate and Professional Student Association

August 2019 - May 2020

Engineering Assembly member

Arizona State University

- · Elected Assembly member for The Polytechnic School.
- · Served in the Engineering Committee and the Special Projects Committee.

# Mechanical Engineering Students Association

August 2015 - May 2016

Student President Mumbai University affiliated college

- · Handled the day-to-day operations of the association.
- · Spearheaded a 2-tier team of 30 people to successfully conduct professional shows, exhibitions and talks for Yantram 2016 (a technical event).
- · Organised event related to technical and professional advancement.

# Mechanical Engineering Students Association

August 2014 - May 2015

Treasurer

Mumbai University affiliated college

· Handled the monetary operations and the budgeting for the association.

## **SKILLS**

- Computer Aided Design/Drawing (SolidWorks, Fusion 360, ProE)
- Matlab Programming (Matlab and Simulink)
- Python Programming
- Limited C++ Programming Skills
- Operation of various Manipulator Arms (Baxter Dual-Arm Robot, UR5, Dobot Magician and self-built arm)
- Limited ROS Capability
- Limited Embedded Systems Capability
- Bio-mechanical Analyses
- OpenSim Simulation (Human Bio-mechanical Modelling)
- Motion Capture and Data Analysis (Vicon and Optitrack systems)
- Fabrication of Various Devices